# Patrick Dugan

www.dailydoog.com dugan.pat@gmail.com 716.481.5567

## Experience

#### **Product Designer, Nextdoor Inc.**

June 2014 to Present :: San Francisco, CA

I currently work at Nextdoor in the role of Product Designer. I joined Nextdoor in June of 2014 as a member of the Designer Fund Bridge program. At Nexdoor I work primairly on our company's Android and web applications in both a product design and frontend development capacity.

#### Technical Strategist, Google Inc.

March 2011 to August 2013:: Mountain View, CA

I worked as a member of the Google Wallet team in an internal development capacity. In this role I helped create models that proactively identified fraud occurring across Google's payment platforms. I additionally worked as an interaction designer within Google Research and as a member of the Google Transparency Reporting team.

#### Technical Development Program, Liberty Mutual Insurance Group

May 2010 to March 2011:: Boston, MA

I participated in the Liberty Mutual Technical Development program and was a member of the company's first mobile development team. In this role I helped design and build Liberty's first Android, iOS, and mobile-web based applications. Additionally, I conducted user research across a number of Liberty's consumer facing mobile and desktop based applications.

#### Systems Analyst (Intern), Polaris Global Mobility Software

March 2010 to May 2011 :: Bellevue, WA

I tested and filed bugs against custom integrations of an expatriate employee payroll management solution. Additionally, I provided technical assistance and support for Fortune 500 clients that included Thomson Reuters, Johnson & Johnson, and Goldman Sachs. I also lead a project to develop an internal collaborative knowledge-sharing repository.

### Education

Graduate

#### **University of Washington**

2013 to 2014 :: Seattle, WA

Master of Science; Human Computer Interaction (In progress); GPA: 3.89

Undergraduate

#### **University of Washington**

2008 to 2010 :: Seattle, WA

Bachelor of Arts; Information Systems; GPA: 3.54

Individual Study

#### College of San Mateo

2011 to 2013 :: San Mateo, CA

Computer Science (Individual Study); GPA: 4.0

#### San Francisco Academy of Art University

2012 to 2013 :: San Francisco, CA

Web Design & New Media (Individual Study); GPA: 3.8

# Frontend & Markup

CSS Jinja2

jQuery HTML5

### Tools

Pixate Sketch Illustrator Balsamiq Framer.js

Fireworks Photoshop

#### **Databases**

mySQL

#### Languages

Java Swift Python Javascript

#### **IDEs**

Coda Xcode Android Studio

# **Frameworks**Android

Android App Engine

#### Design

Heuristic Evaluation Cognitive Walkthrough Low & Hi-Fi Prototyping

#### Research

Card Sorting Task Analysis Contextual Inquiry Think-Aloud Protocol

#### About Me

I enjoy creating elegant, useful and usable user-experiences

I love hiking, camping, running and generally anything that involves being outdoors

I have also maintained a personal blog since early 2011

Patrick Dugan Resume :: 1 of 2

www.dailydoog.com :: dugan.pat@gmail.com :: 716.481.5567

# Selected Projects

#### **Nextdoor Events**

October 2014 to March 2015:: Nextdoor:: San Francisco, CA

- · Led design efforts on android and desktop + responsive web for new event creation and consumption user interfaces
- · Assisted web and android engineering teams in front-end implementation of design work
- · Helped define privacy model for the first publicly shareable user created content on any Nextdoor platform

#### **USMC Pro-Fitness Android Application**

February 2012:: Freelance:: San Francisco, CA

- Designed, developed, and published an android fitness tracking application
- Drove 15,000+ unique application installs
- · Conducted usabilty studies with active duty Marines leading to implementation of actionable improvements

#### **Google Event Connect**

October 2012 to August 2013 :: Google, Mountain View, CA

- Drafted and prototyped improved visual redesign for major components of an internal event planning application
- · Built functional HTML/CSS/Javascript prototypes for use by relevant stakeholder groups within Google Research
- · Consolidated information architecture while also improving event creation, discovery, and logistics management user-flows

# Additional Experience

#### Codepath iOS (Swift) for Designers Bootcamp

May 2015 to July 2015 :: Codepath :: San Francisco, CA

#### **Design Lab Mentor**

September 2014 to Present :: Trydesignlab.com :: San Francisco, CA

#### **Designer Fund Bridge Program**

May 2014 to Present :: Designer Fund (Bridge III) :: San Francisco, CA

#### **University of Washington Human Computer Interaction Graduate Research Assistant**

June 2013 to June 2014:: University of Washington:: Seattle, WA

#### University of Washington Undergraduate Research Learning Community Mentor

September 2013 to January 2014 :: University of Washington :: Seattle, WA

#### **University of Washington Information Systems Undergraduate Mentor**

September 2009 to June 2010 :: University of Washington :: Seattle, WA

#### **University of Washington Resident Adviser**

September 2009 to June 2010 :: University of Washington HFS :: Seattle, WA

#### **United States Marine Corps Officer Candidate**

June 2009 to September 2009 :: USMC Officer Candidate School :: Quantico, VA

#### **Buffalo Geen Art Web Developer (Intern)**

May 2008 to September 2008 :: Buffalogreenart.com :: Buffalo, NY

#### **Boy Scouts of America: Eagle Scout**

March 2005 :: Boy Scouts of America :: Buffalo, NY

Patrick Dugan Resume :: 2 of 2 www.dailydoog.com :: dugan.pat@gmail.com :: 716.481.5567